Guide to the New York State College of Agriculture. Dept. of Rural Sociology surveys, 1938-1966.
New York State College of Agriculture. Dept. of Rural Sociology surveys, 1938-1966.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State College of Agriculture. Dept. of Rural Sociology surveys, 1938-1966.
21-33-1485
New York State College of Agriculture. Dept. of Rural Sociology.
172.7 cubic ft.
Schedules, interviewers' notes, correspondence, records and studies.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection includes schedules, interviewers' notes, correspondence, and other records containing information on individuals, households, farms, neighborhoods, and organizations gathered during the following projects in New York and elsewhere.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection includes schedules, interviewers' notes, correspondence, and other records containing information on individuals, households, farms, neighborhoods, and organizations gathered during the following projects in New York and elsewhere: Farm Security Administration study of non-commercial agriculture, Grundy and Reynolds Counties, Mo., Orange Co., Vt., Beltrami Co., Minn., Oglethorpe and Laurens Counties, Ga., Grayson Co., Va., Mercer Co., W. Va., and Knox Co., Tenn. (1938-42); social participation of farm families, Cortland Co. (1939); rural community organizations, Broome Co. (1939); social status of rural households in low income areas, Otsego, Steuben, and St. Lawrence Counties (1940); families on marginal farmlands, Town of Erin, Chemung Co. (1940); social stratification in a rural community, Spencer, Tioga Co. (1940); and the rural community in wartime, Waterville, Oneida Co. (1944).
Also, studies of community and organizational leadership, Waterville (1946); rural community development, Schuyler Co. (1947, 1957), Richfield Springs, Otsego Co., Van Hornesville, Herkimer Co. (1948, 1958); community voluntary organizations, Odessa Central School District, Schuyler Co. (1948); participation and attitudes of rural young people, Odessa School District (1948); the provision and use of health services in rural New York, Cortland and Otsego Counties (1949-50), 1957-58, 1960), Chautauqua and Livingston Counties (1950-51, 1958-60), Clinton and Ulster Counties (1951-52, 1959-60); farmers' knowledge of, participation in, and and suggestions concerning agricultural programs (1951); social change in a rural community, Brooktondale and Slaterville Springs, Tompkins Co. (1951); personal adjustment of residents in homes for the aged, Ithaca, Tompkins Co., Oxford, Chenango Co., and Red Hook, Dutchess Co. (1951); social change, Marathon, Cortland Co. (1954); dairy farm practice adoption, Richfield Springs and Van Hornesville (1956); study of organizations, Odessa School District and Richfield Springs School District (1957-58); attitudes of rural high school students toward occupations, Odessa, Richfield Springs, Van Hornesville, and Trumansburg Central Schools (1958); migration plans of high school seniors, St. Lawrence Co. (1962); social analysis of Southold, Southold Township, Long Island, N.Y. (1964); and a New York State farm labor study (1966).
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Agriculture.; Cornell University.; United States.Farm Security Administration.
Subjects:
Agriculture--Social aspects.; Community development.; Country life.; Dairying.; Farmers--Socioeconomic status.; Nursing home patients.; Rural conditions.; Rural development.; Rural families.; Rural health services.; Rural poor.; Rural youth.; Social change.; Sociology, Rural.
Places:
New York (State); Grundy County (Mont.); Reynolds County (Mont.); Orange County (Vt.); Beltrami County (Minn.); Oglethorpe County (Ga.); Laurens County (Ga.); Grayson County (Va.); Mercer County (W. Va.); Knox County (Tenn.); Broome County (N.Y.); Cortland County (N.Y.); Otsego County (N.Y.); Steuben County (N.Y.); St. Lawrence County (N.Y.); Chemung County (N.Y.); Tioga County (N.Y.); Spencer (N.Y.); Waterville (N.Y.); Oneida County (N.Y.); Schuyler County (N.Y.); Richfield Springs (N.Y.); Van Hornesville (N.Y.); Herkimer County (N.Y.); Chautauqua County (N.Y.); Livingston County (N.Y.); Clinton (N.Y.); Ulster County (N.Y.); Brooktondale (N.Y.); Slaterville Springs (N.Y.); Tompkins County (N.Y.); Ithaca (N.Y.); Oxford (N.Y.); Chenango County (N.Y.); Red Hook (N.Y.); Dutchess County (N.Y.); Marathon (N.Y.); Odessa (N.Y.); Trumansburg (N.Y.); Southold (N.Y.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Questionnaires.; Photographs.; Color slides.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Survey records restricted to permission of the Archivist. Original investigator shall have unrestricted access to and use of records.
RELATED MATERIALS
Listing of publications and theses based upon these records is available.
CONTAINER LIST
- Adams, How, Larson, 1966, N.Y.S. Farm Worker Management Project; Cottrell and Bee, 1938 Marathon (Cortland Co.) Community Study. (Box 1)
- same; also Anderson and Plambeck, 1939. Social Participation of Family, Cortland Co. (Box 2-5)
- Anderson and Hudson, 1940, Social Status of Rural Households in 3 low income areas of N.Y.S.: Steuben, Otsego, and St. Lawrence Co. (Box 6-7)
- Anderson and Grigsby, 1940, Families on Marginal Farm Lands, Town of Erin, Chemung Co. (Box 8)
- Cottrell and Kaufman, 1940, Social Stratification in a rural N.Y. Community. Spencer, Tioga Co. (Box 9)
- same; also Anderson and Thomas, 1944, rural community in wartime, Waterville, Oneida Co. (Box 10-13)
- same; also Williams and White, 1946, Community organization leadership, Waterville, Oneida Co. (Box 14)
- same; also Anderson, Larson and Halloul, 1951, Social Change in a N.Y. rural community, Slaterville Springs and Brooktondale, Tompkins Co. (Box 15-17)
- same (Box 18-19)
- Moe, Larson, Cummings, 1951, N.Y. Farmers knowledge of agricultural programs (schedules have been discarded); Anderson and Longest, 1954, Social Changes in the Marathon Community, Cortland Co., 1929-1954. (Box 20-21)
- same; also Polson and Fosen, 1955, Dairy Farm Practice Adoption, Towns of Columbia and Warren, Richfield Springs and Van Hornesville Communities, Herkimer and Otsego Counties. Polson and Fosen, 1956, Study of Reference Groups, Town of Columbia and Warren, Richfield Springs and Van Hornesville Communities, Herkimer and Otsego Counties. (Box 22)
- same; also Crawford, 1962, St. Lawrence County High School Seniors' mobility plans. (Box 23-24)
- same; also Larson, 1938-1941, Non-commercial project. (Box 25-26)
- same; also Larson and Capener, 1948, Odessa organizations; Larson and Young, 1957, Odessa organizations, Thurston County, Washington, participants in Farm Security Administration project, 1938-1941. (Box 27)
- Larson and Klein, 1948, Odessa youth. (Box 28)
- same; also Larson and Schwartzweller, 1958, youth attitudes in 4 communities: Trumansburg, Odessa, Richfield Springs, Van Hornesville. (Box 29-31)
- same; also Larson, 1947, Odessa farmer, homemaker schedules re: practices, participation, and attitudes. (Box 32)
- same (Box 33-49)
- Larson, 1957, Odessa farmer, homemaker schedules re: practices, participation, and attitudes. (Box 50-65)
- Larson and Moe, 1948, Richfield Springs, Van Hornesville, analyses, reports, codes. (Box 66)
- Joe Crymes thesis surveys, Richfield Springs and Odessa, 1958; information, reports, codes, thesis notes re: studies of Richfield Springs. (Box 67)
- same; also schedules, Larson and Moe, 1948, Richfield Springs, Van Hornesville. (Box 68)
- same (Box 69-80)
- Larson and Moe, Richfield Springs and Van Hornesville, 1958, survey schedule. (Box 81-87)
- same; also Larson and Moe, 1948, Richfield Springs and Van Hornesville, analyses, reports, codes, background information. (Box 88)
- Southold, Suffolk Co., L.I. land use study, 1964, Robert Carroll, background material, sample procedure, schedules. (Box 89)
- Southold surveys completed by respondents (Box 90-92)
- same; also matching Southold survey schedules completed by interviewer. (Box 93)
- Nursing homes, ca. 1951, Taietz, interview schedules, Odd Fellows Home, Ithaca; N.Y. State Women's Relief Corp. Home, Oxford, N.Y. Ward Manor, Red Hook, N.Y. (Box 94-95)
- Ensminger, Broome County Communities, 1939. Interviewers' notes, schedules. (Box 96)
- Sample design, background information, instruction manuals, field procedures, tabulations, N.Y.S. and Chautauqua Co. (Box 97)
- same for Clinton, Cortland, Livingston, Oswego. (Box 98)
- same, Ulster; schedules for Chautauqua Co., 1950-1951. (Box 99)
- Chautauqua Co., 1950-1951; 1960. (Box 100-103)
- same; Clinton Co., 1950-1951. (Box 104)
- same; Clinton Co., 1959-1960 Clinton Co., rural phase (Box 105)
- same (Box 106-107)
- same; Clinton Co. Urban. (Box 108)
- same (Box 109)
- same; Clinton Co. 1960, rural. (Box 110)
- Cortland Co., 1949-1950, rural phase. (Box 111)
- same; Cortland Co., 1957-1958. (Box 112)
- same (Box 113-114)
- Cortland Co., 1960. (Box 115-116)
- Pre-test, urban schedules, 1959; Livingston, 1958-1959. (Box 117)
- same (Box 118-119)
- same; Livingston Co., 1960, urban phase. (Box 120)
- same; Oswego Co., 1949-1950. (Box 121)
- same; Oswego Co., 1957-1958. (Box 122)
- same (Box 123-124)
- same; Oswego Co., 1959-1960, urban phase. (Box 125)
- same (Box 126-127)
- same; Ulster Co., 1951-1952; 1959-1960. (Box 128)
- same (Box 129-130)
- same; Ulster Co., 1960, urban phase. (Box 131)
- same (Box 132-133)
- Community Value Study - Miriam A. Terry (Dolson) 1956
  - Community I (Box 134)
  - Community II through Community II Organization 4 (Box 135)
  - Community II Organization 5 through Community III Organization 3 (Box 136)
  - Community III Organization 4 through Community IV Organization 7 (Box 137)
- Community Value Study - Louis A. Ploch - Odessa 1954
  - B - Di (Box 137)
  - Do - end (Box 138)
- St. Lawrence Study 1963 Questionnaires and Raw Data
  - 1-64 (Box 139)
  - 65-129 (Box 140)
  - 130-194 (Box 141)
  - 195-210, 501-550 (Box 142)
  - 551-586, Miscellaneous Documents (Box 143)
  - Miscellaneous Documents (Box 144)
- This is Your Life - A Study Made in Groton, N.Y. 1956 (Box 145-147)
- Waterloo Study 1963 (Box 148-150)
- Dairy Image Study, 1969 (Box 151-152)
- Agribusiness 0001-0120 (Box 153)
- Agribusiness 0121-0250 (Box 154)
- Agribusiness 2051-2274 (Box 155)
- Agribusiness 2275-2391 (Box 156)
- Misc. (Box 157-158)